<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_0">
    <text>Hello, Stalker!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_1">
    <text>Am I seeing things?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_1_2">
    <text>Hi.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_0">
    <text>You're fine. Help me, please, uncle... I - I'm not just a toy, I'm an assistant, I'm helping someone. I have to find him. It's uncle Kolya, he's somewhere in the Zone. Please...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_1">
    <text>I get it, it's a robot! Interesting contraption.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_2_2">
    <text>Who is he?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_3_0">
    <text>I knew I'd find someone, hurray! Look, are you a good guy or a bad guy? If you're bad, throw me back, and if you're good, help me. Will you help me?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_3_1">
    <text>I'll help. What should I do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_4_0">
    <text>Please, do not throw me away! I'll die here, if no one helps me, and along with me, my friend who needs help!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_4_1">
    <text>Madness.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_5_0">
    <text>Uncle Kolya, afraid he would be robbed, hid me there 6 months ago and went away on business. And then disappeared. More recently, I got slung into the anomaly where you found me during a blowout. We need to find Kolya, I have to know what happened to him. We'll have to follow in his footsteps, and for that I can show you the way.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_5_1">
    <text>How will you do that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_6_0">
    <text>I can recognize places, I feel them. When we get close to the place, I'll give you a signal. So what do you think? Will you help me, kind Stalker?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_6_1">
    <text>Good.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_7_0">
    <text>Thank you, you really are a good guy! Do you know what we should do? We have to go to a Stalker called Tail and ask him about Kolya. If you wonder why we should go see him first, it's because he's Kolya's friend. I've updated your PDA so that it now shows roughly where we may find Tail.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_1_7_1">
    <text>Well, that's a lead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_0">
    <text>Hi master, what did you want?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_1">
    <text>What are you doing here? Who are you?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_2">
    <text>Remind me, what should I do?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_3">
    <text>Do you know something interesting?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_4">
    <text>I have a problem with your request.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_1_5">
    <text>Don't you have to eat?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_2_0">
    <text>I don't know who or what I am. But since I'm aware of myself I must be someone, not something. I don't remember where I come from, but I do remember something: the place I appeared is called "Hospital". Someone must have made a strong wish for me to appear. My friend went there and made a very, very strong wish and then I appeared. One day my friend fell asleep and someone all big and grown-up came and took me with him. It was Nikolai - Uncle Kolya. He came to this area and hid me there.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_2_1">
    <text>Here's how.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_3_1_0">
    <text>We should go to the bar and talk to the Stalker named Tail. He'll tell us about Kolya and it will be easier to find him.</text>
  </string>
   <string id="cheb_2_3_1_0_1">
    <text>Tail said Kolya went to a place called City-32. Let's look for this place.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_3_1_1">
    <text>Got it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4_0">
    <text>I can provide advice, I can tell a story, I can even come up with something myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4_1">
    <text>Where did you learn all that?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone a long time and read the thoughts of Stalkers passing by. What do you say?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0_guid">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone a long time and read the thoughts of Stalkers passing by. Maybe you need advice?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_0_no_talk">
    <text>I've laid in the Zone a long time and read the thoughts of Stalkers passing by. Oh, I wish I had something interesting to tell you, but... I've forgotten. I'll remember it in five minutes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_5_remember">
    <text>Well, remember.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_1">
    <text>Give advice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_2">
    <text>Tell a story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_3">
    <text>How long till the next blowout?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_4">
    <text>Where can I find a good artifact?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_4a_5">
    <text>I don't need anything for now.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_ok">
    <text>Thanks for the advice.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_1">
    <text>If you meet an enemy in the Zone, do not rush to shoot - first make sure that it really is your enemy. Some mercenaries, soldiers, or even bandits will sometimes make peace with loners if they need help.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_2">
    <text>Sometimes in the Zone you'll find old safes, locked with combination locks. It is not always possible to break them open or hack them, but if you do you'll often find interesting stuff. If you encounter such a safe, remember the following.\n1) Their code consists of no more than 4 or 6 digits.\n2) The numbers on the wheel - it's the regular numbers from 0 to 9.\n3)Use logical clues to figure out the code.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_3">
    <text>Some artifacts do not have properties, either positive or negative. However, many of them are still of very high interest to scientists, so do not rush to sell such "useless" looking artifacts: maybe someone else will pay a lot more for them.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_4">
    <text>Some artifacts are invisible to the naked eye. You have to extract them using those gizmos - I forget what they're called. They're peculiar in the sense that they are created only in certain places and at varying intervals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_5">
    <text>Sometimes, instead of valuable loot you might find a book or manuscript. I advise you to think twice before throwing it away or selling it. Even if it sounds ridiculous, you may find some to whom these things are useful among the Stalkers. They may not mind sharing valuable stuff in return, such as interesting intel.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_guidance_empty">
    <text>I feel something is very wrong.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_busy_0">
    <text>Oh, I wish I had something interesting to tell you, but... I've forgotten. I'll remember it in five minutes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_busy_1">
    <text>Good.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story_next">
    <text>[...go ahead...]</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story_empty">
    <text>Something made me forget all the stories... Oh, you shouldn't bother.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_1">
    <text>Once upon a time two Stalkers went to raid for loot together and stumbled upon a very valuable artifact. They immediately rushed to it, bumping their foreheads in their haste! But there was only one artifact and two friends: they needed a solution. They argued again and again, but could not agree. Thought and thought, but to no avail. The first wanted to sell the artifact and split the money, the other wanted to keep such a precious artifact for himself and repay the other with a part of his own loot.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_2">
    <text>They argued all day until someone came by and advised them to talk to Zacharie the Forester, who lived alone in the Hollow. The old man was known to his fellow Stalkers for his wisdom and the fairness of his decisions. The friends went to him. They explained the reason for their dispute and he answered them: "The Zone made you quarrel, She shall reconcile you. Take this thing that you found and put it on the rotten stump just behind my hut."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_3">
    <text>"Cover it with the old bucket that is lying there and wait for three hours, then take a look under the bucket. If the artifact turns blue, the first of you shall have it, and if it turns red, the second." The Stalkers went to Zacharie's garden, found the stump and put the artifact on it, covered the artifact with the bucket, and sat to wait. After waiting one hour, then two, then three, our friend's nerves started to surrender to the pull of the half-a-million ruble artifact! The first of them started to grumble at the second...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_4">
    <text>It went on and on and finally the second snapped and soon there they were, yelling at each other - curses and good old Russian obscenities. They both grabbed their knives, then stopped, waiting to see who would be the first to attack. Suddenly, both noticed that a strange smell was coming from the bucket. One of the former friends cautiously raised its edge and both saw that on the stump, instead of their artifact, there was nothing but an ordinary pile of cow dung.  Judging by the smell, it was pretty fresh.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_5">
    <text>The two Stalkers lost it for a little while until they finally came to their senses, when they immediately rushed to Zacharie. The old man looked at the stump and told them, "It might not be obvious, but that bucket of mine is anomalous. It revealed to you the secret of the artifact! And to think you were ready to get killed for it..." With these words, the Forester spat juicily onto the stump and went into his hut. What happened to our heroes is unknown, but I do know that nobody ever found this artifact again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story1_ok">
    <text>Interesting.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_1">
    <text>Once upon a time an experienced Stalker went looking for loot and didn't return. They waited for him a day, two, and on the third they waited no more... Suddenly on the fourth day he returns and tell everyone: "Guys, I found something - it's unbelievable. Come with me!" A group of six men gathered, well equipped, armed themselves and went with him. A day passes, two - no sign from them, nor hope of one. The other Stalkers started scratching their heads. The ones that went weren't born yesterday, something was clearly not right. </text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_2">
    <text>A second group gathered, about a dozen people; Many were armed to the teeth, high-class rounds, detectors - one stalker even had a RPG pinned on his back. They went and... Yes, you guessed it - never returned! Their comrades grieved for a long time, even made something akin to a monument to them near the entrance of the bar: a cross with a gasmask and a sign with their names. Had a little wake at the 100Rads as commemoration. The head of the "Duty" suddenly became very interested in this matter.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_3">
    <text>He wanted to know what kind of power had emerged in the Zone that almost twenty experienced Stalkers couldn't cope with. He gathered his best scouts and ordered them to find the missing Stalkers and if they couldn't, to at least find the cause for their disappearance. These mens were professionals - athletes, commandos, ninjas! Even before the Zone they had learned how to survive in the jungle with only a knife in hand.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_4">
    <text>They weren't afraid of wild beasts nor anomalies and they could deal bare-handed with not just bandits but also mercenaries. The scouts began the search and went the next day to the supposed place where the missing ones had last been seen - a small abandoned plant. As they approached they smelled a strange chemical smell. The commander of the scouts, an experienced man, immediately ordered his soldiers to put on their gas masks. As they crept in, they saw:</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_5">
    <text>In the middle of the main building was a hefty tank. Around it lay the bodies. The scouts counted a total of eighteen, none of whom moved. Suddenly, from behind a corner jumped out, no, tumbled out, a Stalker with an RPG at the ready. Staggering, he blearily studied the entire company for a long time, and then finally and with difficulty said:\nAttention! Your papers! Comrade Commander, my report: As of eight o'clock in the evening one hundred and seven liters remaining in the main tank - no leaks were found!\nHe then fell asleep, dead drunk.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story2_ok">
    <text>Thank you for the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_1">
    <text>There was once a Stalker nicknamed "Beetle". He had this nick for, as you guessed, his cunning and caution. But one day our Beetle went and screwed up. How? Very simple. He took an order for a rare artifact, but instead of informing the client when he found it he went to the  "100Rads" Bar. Beetle's client was powerful, from beyond the perimeter. "If he's offended," thought Beetle, "better for me not to come back from the Zone!"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_2">
    <text>He thought and thought and decided to cheat his client. And since he was a cunning Stalker, he decided to do it with his mind. "I will fake my own death to him," thought our Beetle, "and then quietly leave the Zone. I don't personally know the client anyway, so all will be well." But for the accident to seem plausible, witesses were needed. Beetle decided to use one of his friends who owed him some money. That friend was called Slavik, and his nickname was Bubble.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_3">
    <text>Beetle, after making careful preparations, asked him to come along with him to the "Rostok" factory. They came to a place unfamiliar to most Stalkers when Beetle, shouting very loudly and waving his arms, fell, or rather jumped, into a prepared and camouflaged pit. At the bottom of the pit lay the fresh corpse of an unlucky Stalker which Beetle had found on the outskirts of the Bar (a bloodsucker had killed the poor soul).</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_4">
    <text>The dead man was wearing the exact same suit as Beetle, had been given the same backpack and weapons, and his face was severely disfigured - all artfully done by Beetle. He didn't foresee one thing though: the night before a hungry snork had gotten into the pit, attracted by the carrion smell of the body. One can only imagine the horror and surprise of poor hapless Bubble, when he saw at the bottom of the pit two Beetles instead of one and even an extra Snork.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_5">
    <text>"Help me!" yelled Beetle in the meantime, lashing out at the mutant. "Just don't shoot, I'll climb! Give me your hand and I'll get out of here!" However, Bubble was not the sort to help someone in a hurry. Having realized that Beetle's chances were rather slim, he turned and walked away, ignoring the cries from the pit. He owed too much to beetle, too, which played a role. Meanwhile, with the hungry, growling snork crawling up to him, our schemer, who had dug the pit himself, found himself in the worst position.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_6">
    <text>Beetle raised his AK, but it snapped - the fall had filled the shutter with dirt. He barely got out of the pit, our sly dog, but paid the price for salvation by letting the snork rip up his legs and back. Limping back to the camp, he learned that mercenaries kidnapped Bubble right out of his tent. Apparently, when the client learned Beetle bailed out on the deal, he began searching through his teammates. Nothing more has been heard of Bubble, while Beetle is now a career Stalker.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story3_ok">
    <text>Well, well...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_1">
    <text>Once upon a time a Stalker was walking through the Garbage when he saw on the side of the road a sitting Fracture and in its paw it held an artifact! The Fracture turned the artifact between his claws, and then slipped it into his jacket and ran. The Stalker followied him. He ran behind the escaping Fracture, who turned out to be quite clever, going around "Springboards", jumping over "Fruit punches", slipping past "Vortexes"! The Stalker carefully stayed on his trail. They ran into a grove where the Fracture jumped and dropped into a burrow under an old stump. The Stalker took his AK and planted the barrel in the hole.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_2">
    <text>He wanted to throw a grenade, but did not - it could have broken the artifact. He sat, unable to catch his breath. Suddenly he hears from the hole a faint voice: "Stalker," it says, "do not shoot at me. Though I'm a mutant, I desire to live. Let's make a deal instead: I give you the artifact and even show you a place where there are a lot more of them, and you let me go." The Stalker answered the mutant, "Good!", thinking to himself, "I'll take the artifacts and shoot the monster, though I'll cause him no suffering." Everyone knows it's best not to turn your back on a Fracture - strike it dead, instead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_3">
    <text>The Fracture climbed out of the hole, beckoned with its claws, and limped off into the bushes, the Stalker after him. They walked a hundred meters and found a clearing with a large stone in the middle of it. The Fracture crawled to the stone and dug into the earth at the base of it with his paws, pulling into the light an old half-rotten backpack, he poured directly on the Stalker's feet about twenty rare artifacts - more than the Stalker usually collected in a week! The Fracture dumped his loot in front of the Stalker and quietly backed away to get back into the forest. But the Stalker was not born yesterday and realized what was happening.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_4">
    <text>The Stalker aimed at the Fracture and said, "Show me the remaining caches, if you don't want me to shorten your tail!"  The freak hissed and groaned. Obviously, it didn't want to part with its findings but the fear is stronger. Leading the Stalker through the forest, they began to empty caches and transfer the contents into the Stalker's backpack. They stuffed the backpack almost to the top, the Stalker having to throw away all his canned food to make place. Then the Fracture said, "There's one cache left, the greatest."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_5">
    <text>The Stalker was delighted and began to imagine how much he would get for his goods and what he would buy with the money. He estimated that it would be enough to buy his dream - a new "Ford". He began dreaming about coming to his hometown not in the stinking train, but in a brand new car, calling out in the courtyard, honking loudly, as if waiting for someone. The neighbours lean out of the window to watch, and he gets out of the car, stands next to it, lights a cigarette, puts his hand on the hood. A new suit, shoes, black sunglasses...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_6">
    <text>His former classmate, Victor, who had laughed on learning he got a job as welder at the plant with his two diplomas, would shut up for once. The Stalker had never seen such a car even at Victor's father's two stores. Now then, the Stalker and the Fracture approached the last place. The Stalker saw among the young pines an aircraft fuselage. A big one, with "Maize" painted on it. How it got there we don't know, however, there are rumors of some extreme athletes who have tried to fly over the Zone in private planes to take pictures, but got lost.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_7">
    <text>The fuselage was all mangled, peeled off the tail, the wings broken, the cockpit crushed. The Fracture approached it, opened the door and climbed in, the Stalker had to wait outside. Keeping watch so that the cunning one didn't run away. From the wreckage suddenly came a loud hiss and out of it pops a hefty Chimera. The thunderstruck Stalker immediately started fleeing. He ran into the woods, stumbling, going around "Springboards", jumping over "Fruit punches", slipping past "Vortexes"! He barely made it. He forgot the loot, only remembering it once he's gotten his breath back at the bar and noticed the backpack is not present.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_8">
    <text>That's the story... but that's not all! We heard that the Stalker saw the Fracture again after a week. He saw it again sitting, that asshole, at the same old place! The man quietly put automatic to his shoulder and was about to take aim. The freak felt something, jumped up and ran away. The Stalker shot once and missed. He approached the spot the Fracture was sitting in and saw his lost backpack. He looked inside - all the canned food he'd thrown away in the woods. The Fracture has not been seen again.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story4_ok">
    <text>Yeah...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_1">
    <text>Once a stranger came to visit the Zone. What he had forgotten in it? It's just what his work was like - to go around the world, to visit the most dangerous places on the planet and then to describe them. He was a journalist and a traveller, and, quite a famous one. He has visited Iraq, Afghanistan, Libya, even the Chechen Republic. He travelled in the wild jungles of Amazon and the african deserts, contacted local hostile tribes, won confidence of these savages, lived among them; described it in books or wrote articles for magazines, such as "National Geographics" or "Science", he even went on TV.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_2">
    <text>And one beautiful day he decided to visit our Zone and see, the Stalkers living here; what they eat, what they drink, what they do in their spare time, et caetera. Our foreigner was especially interested in the local folklore. He was a big connoisseur of literature, knowing russian well, he read Pushkin, Dostoyevsky and Tolstoy in the original. He decided to collect when possible all histories, jokes, legends, and simple fairy tales connected to the Zone and its inhabitants. However, being an experienced man in such affairs, he made his excursion to the Chernobyl zone a secret.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_3">
    <text>Understand: Militaries would not allow it - first, bandits would prey on him - second, mercenaries would scam him on the repayment - third. So he acted on it, simply, reasonably, but with one mistake - making the operation undercover. So here arrives the journalist (that was called James) to our country under another name, having declared at home in England, that he'd go to investigate Sahara's bedouins culture and customs. Here we had friends that helped him make a deal for a sortie in the Zone.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_4">
    <text>They charged him a lot of money for this - and thought he arrived. But the tourist wasn't satisfied with the program of our brave men of Albion, he wanted to dive head first into the atmosphere of danger and risk of a Stalker's life. Our James that didn't go meet African bedouins however soon regretted his decision. All began that at the Perimeter his group was properly shaken by major Ovchinin. I know of this major not from hearsay - he has hardly not beaten me a kidney off on interrogation when I got into a violation of regime at the Cordon.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_5">
    <text>The veteran warrior started his usual "Shaking" on our gallant traveller and his escort. To those that give all their loot and shut the fuck up - all would go well. Skilled Stalkers for whom it is not the first time going in the Zone, they did as such: take a certain sum (not too much, but not copecks either) and without resistance give it to the major, if it grants them access to the Zone without problems. At the same time they'll earn much more in artifact later, if lucky.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_6">
    <text>But he was an indignated lionheart, he protested, appealed to fairness, a military honor, then recalled the European Court of Human Rights... Basically, when "Sonnie" major had finished with the then brave, he hardly had enough forces, to limp to the camp. Our journalist, he rested a bit in bed there to recover. There our veterans tried means to heal him, but have only made it worse - made the foreigner eat things, and he was even worse from it, than from the beating... Cordon's sludge - such a thing: one from it will go well, and others will suffer, I know it myself.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_7">
    <text>And so, as our englishman came back up on his legs, he wanted to reach the Bar as he knew from stories, that there most Stalkers live. Locals decided to accompany. But in kilometers from the camp they were "received" by bandits. Turns out someone amongst our guys is a "rat", having seen enough, visibly, the pricey equipment of the foreigner, the brand of the equipment, and snitched the skinheads. Thank God, the bandits were in good mood and did not begin to play "moose" as they usually do with beginners, that repeated beatings would not have been endured by our journalist.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_8">
    <text>But still he reached the Bar empty-handed, and moreover half-naked - he's been removed the military suit, a gift from an american general and memory of such quiet days in Afghanistan. At the Bar the people did not recognize a celebrity. Stalkers are simple lads, not interested in science and nature, not reading smart magazines. They accepted our James as a tourist - such a thing is rare in the Zone, but it happens. He was lodged with the others, got a share not to feel pity for. And our Englishman got accostumed among the local brotherhood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_9">
    <text>They advised him to get out of the Zone - but he disagreed. He was engaged in his favorite business: record local tales and the stories of skilled Stalkers. Then a new trouble happened to him: his trigger-happy mercenaries. Them, animals, sometimes practicing their accuracy on us, not to lose that skill. A sniper sits someplace and let's go, that scum, shoots men, that go to the bar from looting. He wounds the first one, that fell behind. He starts yelling, blood everywhere. A friend tries to reach for him to help - the sniper shoots him in the forehead.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_10">
    <text>When the unfortunate's comrades start to hesitate, not hasting to get under the bullets then the ugly beast begins to shoot the wounded man's fingers or ears... A swine, in a word. And so, our journalist gets to see how lost the mercenary has got. He shoots him in the calves, first right, then left - so that no leg feels wronged. This way, or another - the sniper's bullets stop whistling near temples. The poor fellow already ceased to shout, resigned. Then someone from the "Duty" brought a smoke grenade and under the cover of a smoke screen dragged the poor man from under the firing.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_11">
    <text>Our hero strongly changed after that - before, he was, all joking, laughing, and now he has become serious, tight-lipped. Some said that after the accident he's been heard a couple times as he cried softly at night. But that's nothing - the foreigner had grown accustomed to a Stalker's life, drank it all up, recognized his grief, and rejoiced. There's one thing he really needed in his heart. In the Zone wounded up some makeshift scribblings: improvised manuscript with stories about life here started to spread around. Some funny, some others - terrible, and others - sad.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_12">
    <text>Probably, some former student engaged in this deed, one that lived up the first anomalies. But the second our James saw these pieces of paper - he began to shake: it was what he needed! He long made inquiries about that unknown author, all tried to find him. But he disappeared, apparently, that odd fellow - nobody found more of his manuscripts on old yellow pages of Soviet papers. Then James began to ask all Stalkers to bring him these "books" for collection. However, he's a trader now. That's the fate of such history.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story5_ok">
    <text>Yeah, that's what happens...</text>
  </string>
<!-- end of the file coming soon -->
</string_table>
