<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="cheb_story6_1">
    <text>Among all the benefits available for Stalkers, the one Vintar loved most was money. No one knew exactly what he collected in two years and a half of life in the Zone, but there were rumours that it was fantastic. As you would expect, greedy was our Vintar, like a vacuum cleaner for loot. He always went alone even in dangerous places so as not to share profits with assistants and he never bought lock picks with him. Other stalkers disliked him for this, but also respected him.  Vintar knew that working hard was the key to success and he amassed all his loot on his own, neither danger nor hard work made him hesitate.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_2">
    <text>It's told, that once he dragged by himself in the Bar an old Soviet safe found somewhere in a cellar to saw it open. What was inside the safe and whether there was something at all - thing like that are better left unsaid, but it is known only, that the burden only weighed under a hundred kgs. Although many, of course don't believe it... These don't know Vintar. Or rather, didn't know. Where has he kept his money? - you ask. Kept in the same safe, but not only. He welded it to the metal floor of the Bar, put a lock with a code on the door, and every month would slip the bartender a handful of artifacts for the protection of his private "cell".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_3">
    <text>A recurring joke at the Bar was, that when it's time for Vintar from the Zone to go, taking out all his goods, he will give it to the fighters, like Ostap Bender in "The Little Golden Calf". Our hero did not trust electronic money at all. Joke was Vintar never responded and in general conducted the closed way of life: he wasn't friend with anyone and didn't clash with anyone, trusting nobody. He had a quiet character, but had a reputation of being gloomy and reticent, prefering to act, than to reason. Outside of the Perimeter he would be a large businessman or a money-bag, though who knows...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_4">
    <text>Somehow on the next spring our hero was going on a new raid God knows where - his plan, you guessed it, again, he didn't share with anyone. A day passed, then another, then a week, but Vintar did not return. Normally a Stalker raid for loot takes only three, maybe four days, the Zone, though it's large, but on a week you can make the walk around, of course, ignoring the anomalies and other things... But two more days passed, and Vintar did not return. I must tell you that at the Bar was such an unwritten law, or rather, a custom that if a Stalker perished in the Zone, his property was given to his next of kin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_5">
    <text>And if there were none, it would go to a friend or partner. The barman had just began to think with Stalkers, to whom would obtain Vintar's property, when out of nowhere, some Stalker appeared. He declared the following: with Vintar they were the best of friends since childhood and now the missing's property belonged to him. "He had no family, his parents died long ago" - our new friend sighed, - "and I was like a brother to him, I protected him, took care of him". As proof of his words he showed some old fuzzy photographs, where they were captured together with Vintar during military service.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_6">
    <text>The most experienced Stalkers gathered for council (the cas was not ordinary, it was the fate of the big money - the worth if Vintar's years of looting) and began to settle. Some of the Stalkers suggested to find out, whether there were relatives of the victim and send part of the money to them, and divide the rest amongst them, so to say, for the costs. But the others believed Vintar's freshly baked friend and entrusted the business to him. So the safe with goods passed to the new owner.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_7">
    <text>Perhaps, you will think, that the given decision was too precipitated or even naive, however it is necessary to note, that the Stalkers on this council were not fools and the majority understood, that if outside the Perimeter huge money is success, here, in the Zone - it is more likely a problem. Gangsters, thugish mercenaries, envious "friends" - the laws here are different. But shall we return to our sheeps, or rather, to the money. Having acquired the right to open the safe, Vintar's friend vigorously started his business.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_8">
    <text>However straight-off opening of the cache did not happen - the code for the lock was known only of the previous owner. Not really bothered, our new acquaintaance brought first a Pudova sledgehammer, but when it didn't help - a propane torch. Separating, at last, the metallic door of centimeters of metal, the Stalker was stunned: it was empty inside... Someone, who knew the treasure numbers, hurried in advance and the first has withdrawn its property! However taking a closer look, he saw at the bottom some bundle. Reaching into the depth of the ruined safe, the Stalker took from it a thick notebook wrapped in foil.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_9">
    <text>He opened it and before his eyes appeared some incomprehensible inscriptions: squares, zigzags, squiggles, and figures - a sea of figures. Inscriptions and figures - that's all the goods Vintar, he left to them as legacy... However, it looks like you already understood, that it was not exactly so. The newfound "millionaire" also understood this, therefore he has shown the Barman and some stalker the notebook for an interpretation. "It's a code" - realized the Barman, - "the dead encyphered a map, to where can be found his savings".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_10">
    <text>However, a scientist who happened to be in the Bar has denied this hypothesis - Dr. Gorbovsky (he was involved in the study of a disease that ills Stalkers in the Zone). "This is a mathematical formula" - concluded the doctor, - "but, I can't tell you what it means, because it is not in my field. I, you see, am a biologist". Stalkers understood, that Vintar's money could not have completely disappeared and that in the formulas from the notebook the answer to the question of where it has gotten, most likely, was hidden. However among Stalkers are no mathematicians, therefore this question is without answer...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_11">
    <text>It's long been an habit in the Bar to discuss this history behind a pint of beer. One theorized, that Vintar was not really lost, and all this time the sly simply quietly sent money out of the Perimeter, the safe used as a distraction and when the time came, has simply fallen down from the Zone and disappeared; others claimed, that he was actually a latent scientist or as we say here, a "nugget", that is to say a unique person. Having solved the mathematical riddle of the Zone's laws, he could deduce a method of determining the places where most of the artifacts will appear and use it to his needs...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_12">
    <text>A wide variety of guesses were made by them, but no one ever saw Vintar, nor his money. And the notebook lies somewhere under a counter at the Barman's. If you're in the area and give a glance in the Bar "100Rads", you can ask to see it, it's free. And if you are versed into mathematics, can defend against various theorems - then you have a chance to receive a key to the solution of this affair. For now it remains a mistery.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_ok">
    <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_0">
    <text>What are you working on?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_1">
    <text>"The old house Mystery"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_2">
    <text>"A strange anomaly"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_3">
    <text>"Safe digger"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_4">
    <text>"The anomaly in the tower"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_5">
    <text>"Flying islands"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_6">
    <text>"The conflict at the sawmill"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_7">
    <text>"Fleas hideout"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_8">
    <text>"The trap at the gas station"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_9">
    <text>The issue of Immortality - p. 1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_0">
    <text>A bad-bad person! Very bad! He has killed the good person, calamity! To the good person it is bad, he wishes to sleep... Help it to fall asleep, I can hear, how he is angry, he grumbles, he shouts! Find the four parts of the good person here, in the court yard. They're hidden very-very well: on a roof, on a tree, in a car and in some electronic contraption.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_1">
    <text>Clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_0">
    <text>Look around, do you see portals? You need to find the proper sequence of four portals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_1">
    <text>Yeah, I'm on it...</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_0">
    <text>The inscriptions on the safe, they mean something abbreviated. What is it? And could it be, next to the inscriptions stand numerals? They should be only four. By the way, remember: the divisions on the wheel of the safe account for figures from 0 up to 9, it's necessary to make a code or cipher of them. Got it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_0">
    <text>Oh, what a nasty sound! We should switch it off, and the person in the tower will die! The sound comes from the box with the buttons. First press all the buttons from top to bottom, then bottom left. Then again from top to bottom.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_1">
    <text>Understood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_0">
    <text>Master, I know, what to do! Try to find a portal, which will lead you in this lodge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_1">
    <text>Clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_0">
    <text>Oh, once again thre are bad people! So there is a lot of them, they're more, than good people... The bad peoples want to trick the good peoples, they will suggest peace. But as soon as the good people will agree, they can die.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_1">
    <text>I will take a note.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_0">
    <text>The small person has lost a bag and is now punished for it, he is in a corner... What to do? We have to find the bag and all will be well. It is somewhere nearby, under a shrub near a fence... Don't forget to read, what you find in it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_1">
    <text>Good.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_0">
    <text>Oh, where is it we are? That is a terrible room, people died here, they died long ago... Here is uncomfortable. And to leave is impossible - something wont let us. We need to open that old safe and to find in one good thing which will help. The code of the safe? We shall give it some thoughts. Earlier, a long time ago, people brought fuel here for transports. Fuel was designated by numbers... These numbers are written in colums! I hope, that you have remembered them, master? Try to enter these numbers. The code is four-digits.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_1">
    <text>That's clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_muten">
    <text>My dead Uncle told me, that the Cobblestone should be looked for around great metallic designs. As those in the Garbage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_firefly">
    <text>"For the Firefly it is necessary to wander on water, or during a rain. Brrr, I do not like to get wet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_chameleon">
    <text>The Chameleon can only be found during blowouts. Maybe we wont find it, heh?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_common">
    <text>All the things that you have found, we need to bring to my lifeless uncle.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_1">
    <text>Thanks for your help</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
