<?xml version="1.0" encoding="windows-1251"?>
<string_table>
  <string id="cheb_story6_1">
    <text>Among all the benefits available for Stalkers, the one Vintar loved most was money. No one knew exactly what he collected in two years and a half of life in the Zone, but there were rumours that it was fantastic. As you would expect, greedy was our Vintar, like a vacuum cleaner for loot. He always went alone even in dangerous places so as not to share profits with assistants and he never bought lock picks with him. Other stalkers disliked him for this, but also respected him.  Vintar knew that working hard was the key to success and he amassed all his loot on his own, neither danger nor hard work made him hesitate.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_2">
    <text>It's said that he once dragged an old Soviet safe found somewhere in a cellar to the Bar to saw it open. What was in the safe and even whether there was anything at all - things like that are better left unsaid, all we know is that the burden weighed around a hundred kilos. Many don't believe it, but they don't know Vintar. Or rather, didn't know. Where did he keep his money, you ask?  He kept in that same safe. He welded it to the metal floor of the Bar, put a lock with a code on the door, and every month would slip the bartender a handful of artifacts for the protection of his private "stash."</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_3">
    <text>A recurring joke at the Bar was that when it's time for Vintar to leave the Zone taking all his loot, he will give it to the fighters like Ostap Bender in "The Little Golden Calf." Our hero did not trust electronic money at all. Joke was Vintar never responded and in general kept to himself: he wasn't friends with anyone nor did he clash with anyone, trusting nobody. He was a quiet man, but had a reputation of being gloomy and reticent, prefering to act than to think. Outside of the Zone he would have been a successful businessman or a rich man, though who knows.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_4">
    <text>The next spring our hero was going on a new raid God knows where - you guessed it, as usual, he didn't share his plan with anyone. A day passed, then another, then a week, but Vintar did not return. Normally a Stalker raiding for loot takes only three, maybe four days.  The Zone is large, but you can walk all over it in a week, ignoring the anomalies and other things in it of course. But two more days passed, and Vintar did not return. I must tell you that at the Bar there was an unwritten law, or rather, a custom that if a Stalker perished in the Zone, his property was given to his next of kin.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_5">
    <text>And if there were none, it would go to a friend or partner. The barman had just began to discuss who should be given Vintar's property with the Stalkers when out of nowhere a Stalker appeared. He declared that Vintar and he were the best of friends since childhood and now the missing Vintar's property belonged to him. "He had no family, his parents died long ago," our new friend sighed, "and I was like a brother to him. I protected him and took care of him." As proof of his words he showed some fuzzy old photographs standing with Vintar during military service.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_6">
    <text>The most experienced among the Stalkers gathered for council and started to discuss the issue (this wasn't common, it was due to the sums of money involved - the accumulated value of Vintar's years of looting). Some of these Stalkers suggested finding out whether there were any living relatives of the victim and send part of the money to them, and then divide the rest amongst themselve for their costs, so to say. But the others believed Vintar's freshly baked friend and entrusted everything to him. So the safe with Vintar's goods passed to the new owner.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_7">
    <text>You may think, perhaps, that their decision was too quick or even naive, however note that the Stalkers on this council were not fools and the majority understood that even if outside the Zone huge sums money are a sign of success, here in the Zone it is more likely a problem. Gangsters, thuggish mercenaries, envious "friends" - the laws here are different. But let's return to our story. Having acquired the right to open the safe, Vintar's friend got straight to work.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_8">
    <text>The safe refused to open easily - the code for the lock was known only to the previous owner. Not really bothered, our new acquaintance first brought a Pudova sledgehammer and when it didn't help, a propane torch. Removing, finally, the metallic door centimeters of metal thick, the Stalker was stunned: the safe was empty. Someone who knew the code for the lock had got there first and taken its contents! Looking closer he saw a bundle. Reaching into the back of the ruined safe the Stalker took from it a thick notebook wrapped in foil.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_9">
    <text>He opened the notebook and saw some incomprehensible scribbles: squares, zigzags, squiggles, and figures - a sea of figures. Inscriptions and figures - that's all the loot Vintar as a legacy. However, as you may have guessed, that wasn't all he had left. The newfound "millionaire" also understood this, and showed the Barman and another Stalker the notebook for their opinion on the scribbles. "It's a code," realized the Barman, "the dead man left a cryptic map to where he hid his savings".</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_10">
    <text>A scientist who happened to be in the Bar disagreed with this, a Dr. Gorbovsky (he was involved in the study of a disease afflicting Stalkers in the Zone). "This is a mathematical formula," concluded the doctor, "but I can't tell you what it means, because it is not in my field. I am a biologist, you see." The Stalkers knew that Vintar's money could not have disappeared and that the question of where it was hidden was probably answered by the formulas in the notebook. There being no mathematicians among the Stalkers, this question had no answer.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_11">
    <text>It's long been a habit in the Bar to discuss this story with a pint of beer. One Stalker guess that Vintar was not really lost, and all this time the sly one had quietly sent money out of the Zone. The safe was used as a distraction and when the time came, Vintar had simply dropped out of the Zone and disappeared. Others claimed that he was actually an underground scientist or as we say here, a "nugget", that is to say a unique person. Having solved the mathematical riddle of the Zone's laws, he had deduced a method of determining the places where most artifacts would appear and used it to his own ends.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_12">
    <text>A lot of guesses were made by the people that came to the Bar but no one ever saw Vintar or his money again. And the notebook still lies somewhere under a counter at the Barman's. If you're in the area and drop by the "100Rads" Bar, you can ask to see it - it's free. And if you are well versed in mathematics, you have a chance at finding a key to the solution of this affair. For now it remains a mystery.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_story6_ok">
    <text>Thanks for the story.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_0">
    <text>What are you working on?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_1">
    <text>"The mystery of the old house"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_2">
    <text>"A strange anomaly"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_3">
    <text>"Safe digger"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_4">
    <text>"The anomaly in the tower"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_5">
    <text>"Flying islands"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_6">
    <text>"The conflict at the sawmill"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_7">
    <text>"Flea's hideout"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_8">
    <text>"The trap at the gas station"</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_btn_9">
    <text>The issue of Immortality - p. 1</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_0">
    <text>A bad, bad person! Very bad! He killed the good person, what a calamity! To the good person it is bad, he wishes to sleep... Help it to fall asleep, I can hear, how he is angry, he grumbles, he shouts! Find the four parts of the good person here in the court yard. They're hidden very, very well: on a roof, in a tree, in a car and in some electronic contraption.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_1_1">
    <text>Clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_0">
    <text>Look around, do you see portals? You need to find the proper sequence of four portals.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_2_1">
    <text>Yeah, I'm on it.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_0">
    <text>The inscriptions on the safe mean something abbreviated. What is it? And are those numbers next to the inscriptions? There should be only four. Keep in mind, by the way: the divisions on the wheel of the safe are the numbers from 0 to 9, it's necessary to make a code or cipher out of them. Got it?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_3_1">
    <text>Yes.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_0">
    <text>Oh, what a nasty sound! We should switch it off and the person in the tower will die! The sound comes from the box with the buttons. First press all the buttons from top to bottom, then bottom left. Then again from top to bottom.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_4_1">
    <text>Understood.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_0">
    <text>Master, I know what to do! Try to find a portal, which will lead you to this lodge.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_5_1">
    <text>Clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_0">
    <text>Oh, once again there are bad people! So there are a lot of them, they're more than the good people. The bad people want to trick the good people, they will suggest peace. But as soon as the good people agree, they will be killed.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_6_1">
    <text>I will keep that in mind.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_0">
    <text>The small person has lost a bag and is now being punished for it, he is sitting in a corner. What to do? We have to find the bag and all will be well. It is somewhere nearby, under a shrub near a fence. Don't forget to read what you find in it!</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_7_1">
    <text>Good.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_0">
    <text>Oh, where are we? This is a terrible room, people died here, long ago. It's uncomfortable here. And leaving is impossible - something won't let us. We need to open that old safe and find in it a good thing which will help us. The code to the safe? We shall give it some thought. Earlier, a long time ago, people brought fuel here for the transports. Fuel was designated by numbers. These numbers are written in columns! I hope you remember them, master? Try to enter these numbers. The code is four digits long.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_8_1">
    <text>That's clear.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_muten">
    <text>My dead Uncle told me that the Cobblestone should be looked for around great metallic designs. Like those in the Garbage.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_firefly">
    <text>"For the Firefly, you have to search around water or during a storm. Brrr, I do not like to get wet.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_chameleon">
    <text>The Chameleon can only be found during blowouts. Maybe we wont find it, huh?</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_common">
    <text>We need to bring all the things that you have found to my lifeless uncle.</text>
  </string>
  <string id="cheb_2_5_9_1">
    <text>Thanks for your help.</text>
  </string>
</string_table>
